Business – Technology – Delivery

Professional breadth and depth of skills with domain knowledge of Marketplace / Open source technology obtained from experiences implementing and enabling business processes to deliver transformational uses of technology, delivered within an Agile Project Management framework. Ambitious and enthusiastic, ability to learn and adapt quickly and provide results under pressure.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## AWS Cloud Engineer - Container AideR LLC, New York, NY

September 2015 – On-going

Platform as a Service - providing a Real-Time Spatial Optimization Engine. A tool to deliver optimal loading solutions in a client rich Front-End web application, REST API's, API Gateway and Micro services Architecture.

- Develop Amazon AMI Marketplace products of auto-scalable, highly available, fault tolerant systems.
- Automate Deployment processes though creation of Chef Resource files, CloudFormation Templates and Ansible Playbooks.
- Integrate real-time non-blocking I/O, event driven web applications as a Front-end User-interface to analytics.
- Design API Gateways for client access using Micro services architecture.
- Lift and shift of an existing on-premises application to Amazon Web Services (AWS). (AWS CloudFormation, AWS CodePipeline, Ansible, Chef, MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js, StrongLoop)

# **Developer - FinTech - Vanare LLC**, New York, NY

October 2015 - December 2015

"Vanare is a next-generation wealth management platform built on roboadvisor DNA. It is fully customizable to your investment philosophy, workflows and way of doing business." - Technology / Product

- Provide Project Management / Business Analyst support to deliver RFI replies and Product Documentation.
- Manage offshore development teams to resolve product deliverables.
- Support Modular design, Document system Process flows and critical path definitions.

  (Atlassian JIRA, PHP Symfony2, Project Pier, MS Project, Postgres, New Relic, JavaScript, Amazon AWS, Ansible)

### Lead Software Engineer - Troy Container Line LTD, Red Bank, NJ

February 2013 – Sept 2015

A Non-Vessel Operating Common Carrier who partners with others to provide individual shippers and freight forwarding services to ensure cargo or freight moving from point of origin to its final destinations.

- Enterprise Architect design Logistics platform in support of NVOCC's operations
- Optimize Load Planning utilizing metaheuristic algorithms in container cell division.
- Port legacy Server/Client solution into Event driven Web Application with Services Oriented Architecture (Publish-Subscribe).
   (Centos 6.5 Linux, Apache 2.2, MySQL 5.0, Php 5.4, Sybase, Bootstrap 3.0, jQuery 2.1.1, HTML5, Eclipse Juno, Java 7)

#### Solutions Architect - BTi3 Global LLC, Washington D.C.

August 2010 - January 2013

An Independent Software Vendor (ISV) of electronic trading platforms, capitalize on Market interventions of Q.E.

- Execute algorithmic trading strategies within suitability models of trading constraints using genetic optimization algorithms of Technical Indicators. Review artifacts of OMS requirements and identify automation opportunities.
- Prepare and review performance reports, risk metrics and attribution details to review risk/allocation metrics such as Value-at-Risk (VaR), mean-variance optimization, Bayesian, Black-Litterman allocation.
- Provide statistical visualizations of the covariance matrix used in Principal Component Analysis.
   (MATLAB, Distributed Computing, Complex Event Processing, Apache Hadoop Ecosystem, R, +KDB)

# Director of Technology - Geneva Enterprises, Inc., Arlington, VA.

June 2006 - August 2010

Rosenthal Automotive is one of the largest private dealership groups with 15 franchises. Provide Franchise Owner Direct Support to identify, obtain and implement technology needs.

- Assess Enterprise / Data Management systems. Convert Client/Server model to Services Oriented Architecture, identify dependencies, determine training requirements, and coordinated project execution.
- Project Management conversion of CRM vendor systems from ADP to Salesforce.com using Informatica ETL.
- Private cloud implementation to deliver virtualization solution of domain EMC NAS/SAN optimization, VMware vSphere configuration, Cisco router configuration vendor neutral networking.

(Eclipse, VM Ware, VSphere, Java 1.5, Citrix, ADP, Salesforce, Autobase, BCM, AS400)

## **EDUCATION / TRAINING**

AWS Solutions Architect - Associate Badge	Self-Paced Labs	2016
Agile Project Management	Unified Process	2010
Bachelor of Science - Business Administration: Economics	Kansas State University - Manhattan, KS	1996
Information Warfare Operator	U.S. Signal Corp. / Special Operations	1991